<resources>
    <string name="app_name">SamuraiBiography</string>
    <string name="samurai_name"> SamuraiName</string>
    <string name="description">Description samurai</string>

    <string-array name="data_name">
        <item>Miyamoto Musashi</item>
        <item>Shimazu Toyohisa</item>
        <item>Shimazu Yoshihiro</item>
        <item>Taira Masakudo</item>
        <item>Takeda Katsuyori</item>
        <item>Takena Kahanbei</item>
        <item>Uesugi Kenshin</item>
        <item>Yamagata Masakage</item>
        <item>Yamakawa Hiroshi</item>
        <item>Yanagisawa Yoshiyasu</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="data_description">
        <item>Miyamoto Musashi (宮本 武蔵), whose real name was Shinmen Bennosuke (新免 辨助?) was born on March 12, 1584 in Ōhara-chō in Mimasaka province and died on May 19, and the most famous fencer in the country history. Miyamoto Musashi (宮本 武蔵), whose real name was Shinmen Bennosuke (新免 辨助?) was born on March 12, 1584 in Ōhara-chō in Mimasaka province and died on May 19, 16451. He is one of the iconic figures of Japan, a master bushi, calligrapher, renowned painter, philosopher and the most famous fencer in the countrys history.His full name was Shinmen Musashi-no-Kami Fujiwara no Harunobu (新免武蔵守藤原玄信?), Musashi-no-kami was an honorary (and obsolete) title dispensed by the imperial court making him the governor of Musashi province (in the area of present-day Tokyo).Fujiwara is the name of the aristocratic lineage to which he belongs. Harunobu was a ceremonial name, similar to a compound name for a sinicized gentleman, notably used by all high ranking samurai and nobles.Miyamoto Musashis grandfather was a very good fencer related to the Akamatsu clan by his lord Shinmen Iga-no-kami who as a reward allowed him to bear his family name.That is why Musashi signed the Book of Five Rings (Go rin no sho) with the name of Shinmen Musashi. Musashis father was known as Muni. Today, he is also known as Munisai, a fictitious name which is a creation of the writer Eiji Yoshikawa.</item>


        <item>Shimazu Toyohisa (島津 豊久; July 1570 - October 21, 1600), also called Houjumaru (豊寿丸), Tadatoyo (忠豊), Tenrei Shōun Tadatoyo (天岑昌運) or Matashichirou (又七郎), was a samurai of the Shimazu clan, son of Shimazu Iehisa, grandson of Shimazu Yoshihiro and lord of Sadowara Castle.He was born in the first year of the Kame era (1570), and was the son of Shimazu Iehisa. His childhood name was Toyojumaru. Initially called Shimazu Tadatoyo, he was later renamed Toyohisa.On June 1, 1583, a vassal of the Shimazu clan, Uwai Satokane, came to the Sadowara basket and Toyohisa received him in place of his father Iehisa who was absent.In April 1584, even before his Genpuku, he fought in the battle of okitanawate, against the vastly superior forces of Ryūzōji Takanobu. Early in the morning, just before this battle, his father, Iehisa, approached the 13-year-old Toyohisa, urging him to retreat.Toyohisa replied in the negative, arguing that a man who, as a young man, had fled a battle and abandoned his father would have lived out the rest of his days in disgrace. In 1587 Toyotomi Hideyoshi invaded the Kyūshū. Shimazu Iehisa and Shimazu Toyohisa, with an army of more than 10,000 soldiers, attacked the vanguard of the Toyotomi army led by Chōsokabe Motochika, Chōsokabe Nobuchika, Sengoku Hidehisa, Sogō Masayasu, which numbered 20,000 men, while crossing the Toji River, and defeated it badly in the battle of Hetsugigawa.Iehisa and Toyohisa killed as many as 3 daimyō in battle: Ryūzōji Takanobu at the Battle of Okitanawate and Chōsokabe Nobuchika and Sogō Masayasu at the Battle of Hetsugigawa; There is no other warlord who defeated so many daimyō in the field during the Sengoku period.On May 24, 1587 he took part with his father in the Battle of Takajō where the Shimazu were defeated and retreated.That same year the Shimazu clan surrendered to Toyotomi Hideyoshi, and on July 10, 1587 Iehisa died suddenly after returning from Toyotomis camp, probably from assassination or poisoning. Shimazu Yoshihiro is said to have ordered it.Also, after his fathers death, Toyohisa was raised by his uncle Yoshihiro as if he were his own son, instructing him in the art of warfare.Whereupon Iehisa praised his sons courage and tied a sash around his waist, saying that if he survived the battle he would untie it and become a man. The Shimazu fought hard at Okitanawate achieving a brilliant victory, and at the end of the battle Iehisa untied the sash to his son.His Genpuku ceremony took place in Higo on May 23, 1584. </item>


        <item>Shimazu Yoshihiro (島津義弘 ; August 21, 1535 - August 30, 1619), also cited as Shimazu Tadahira (島津忠平) and known as Hyogo no kami, was the second son of Shimazu Takahisa . the call to arms and so Yoshihiro had to punish them.He played an important role in kidnapping Korean potters who were brought to Satsuma as prisoners of war. This increased the trade of the province, thanks to the new style of pots, called Satsuma-yaki.During the Battle of Sekigahara in 1600, according to the Edo period novel Rakusuishū (『落 穂 集 ), Yoshihiro was supposed to take Tokugawa Ieyasus side, but was humiliated by Torii Mototada upon arrival at Fushimi Castle and took Ishida Mitsunaris side. </item>


        <item>Masakado was born into a prominent noble lineage, the Kanmu Heishi (or Taira clan descended from Emperor Kanmu). As a young man, he served at the imperial court in the capital and then settled into a life as a country gentleman in the eastern provinces of Japan, northeast of modern Tokyo.he west, it threw the court and the capital into panic and culminated, according to most versions of the story, in the leader claiming for himself the title of "new emperor".Many historians see the incident as a harbinger of the beginning of the events of the late seventeenth, thirteenth and fourteenth centuries, which, step by step, inaugurate the medieval era of the rule of warriors.the drama begins in the second month of 935, when Masakado is suddenly attacked - ambushed - by another local leading warrior, Minamoto Tasuku (dates unknown), at a place called Nomoto, near the convergence of Hitachi, Shimotsuke, Musashi, and Shimōsa provinces.Tasuku is the eldest son of Minamoto Mamoru, a powerful warrior and sometime official of the Hitachi government. The reason for his grudge against Masakado is unclear, but his decision to perpetuate it in the field sets in motion a complex and memorable chain of events.Within months Masakado finds himself at war with several of his relatives. Although taken by surprise, Masakado defeated Tasuku and then retaliated from behind, burning and looting the homes and property of Tasukus supporters in southeastern Hitachi province, and murdering thousands of residents of these settlements.Among the most important victims of the battle of Nomoto and its brutal consequences were Tasuku, his brothers, and his brother-in-law, Taira Kunika (?-935), who was also Masakados uncle.Their death brings Masakado into conflict with two other sons-in-law of Mamoru, the son of Kunika Sadamori (dates unknown) and Masakados paternal uncle and father-in-law of Taira Yoshikane (deceased in 937-938).During the next four years, Masakado took great care to stay within the limits of imperial law. In the ninth month of 936, he received a summons to appear in court to answer charges filed by Minamoto Mamoru but managed to convince the Imperial Police Bureau and the State Council that there were extenuating circumstances for his actions and thus escaped conviction.</item>


        <item>Takeda Katsuyori (jap. 武田 勝頼; b. 1546; April 3, 1582) was a Japanese daimyō of the Sengoku period who assumed leadership over the Takeda clan after the death of his famous father and legendary commander Takeda Shingen. He is one of the most tragic figures in Japanese history because, despite the outstanding importance of his clan in his youth, and, despite all his efforts, he had to witness its downfall. Katsuyori, born Suwa Shirō (諏訪 四郎), later Suwa Katsuyori, defeated his mother Suwa clan and appointed Takatō Castle as his seat of power. After his older brother Takeda Yoshinobu died, Katsuyoris son Nobukatsu became leader of the Takeda clan, allowing Katsuyori to take actual control. After the death of his father Shingen, he took charge of the family and fought with Tokugawa Ieyasu at Takatenjin in 1574 and Nagashino in 1575. He took Takatenjin Castle, which not even his father had been able to do before; which secured him the support of the Takeda clan, but he suffered a terrible defeat at Nagashino, which was due to one of the first recorded uses of fire volleys by the enemy infantry. Oda Nobunaga had about 3000 arquebuses at his disposal and ordered his infantry to entrench behind palisades and fire in rows one after the other. This allowed him to defeat the superior Takeda cavalry and kill a third of all 24 Takeda generals, which was an irretrievable loss for them.</item>


        <item>Takenaka Shigeharu (竹中 重治, September 27, 1544-July 6, 1579), also known as "Hanbei" (半兵衛), was a samurai during the Sengoku period in the 16th century.  He initially served the Saitō clan of Mino province, but fomented an uprising and took control of the Saitō clans castle at Mount Kinka. Toyotomi Hideyoshi was so impressed with this tactic that he invited Shigeharu to join his forces as a strategist. Shigeharu made many contributions to Hideyoshi with his exceptional talent in this field. He died of illness during Hideyoshis attack on the Mōri in the Chūgoku region while Miki Castle was under siege. Takenaka Shigekado, Shigeharus son and successor, continued to serve Hideyoshi after his fathers death. At the battle of Sekigahara, he fought on the side of Tokugawa Ieyasu, and his possessions in Bodaisan were secured for him. The Takenaka family became a hatamoto family and soon left their old castle in Bodaisan for the new castle in Iwate. The Takenaka lands included the village of Sekigahara.</item>


        <item>Uesugi Kenshin (上杉 謙信 February 8, 1530 - April 19, 1578) was a Japanese daimyō who ruled Echigo Province during the Sengoku period of Japanese history. He was one of the most powerful warriors of his time and is famous for his prowess on the battlefield, his legendary rivalry with Takeda Shingen, his military and strategic expertise, and his devotion to the god of war Bishamonten; in fact many of his followers believed that he was the avatar of this deity, so they called him "The God of War". His original name was Nagao Kagetora (長尾景虎). He changed his name later to Uesugi Masatora (上杉政虎) when he inherited the name of the Uesugi clan. He later changed his name back to Uesugi Terutora (上杉輝虎) in honor of the shōgun Ashikaga Yoshiteru and finally to Kenshin (上杉謙信) after becoming a Buddhist monk. He continually refers to Kenshin as the "Dragon of Echigo" due to his martial arts skills demonstrated on the battlefield. His rival, Takeda Shingen, was known as "The Tiger of Kai". In some versions of Chinese mythology (Shingen and Kenshin always had an interest in the culture of China, especially in the works of Sun Tzu), the dragon and the tiger had always been rivals and always tried to defeat each other, but were never able to win definitively.</item>


        <item>Yamagata Masakage (山県 昌景, born in 1524 and died on June 27, 1575) was one of the 24 generals of Shingen Takeda. A Sengoku era samurai in the service of the Takeda clan, he was the younger brother of Toramasa Obu and renowned for being an excellent fighter. Masakage was born into the Iitomi clan, first known as Iitomi Genshirō, then as Obu Saburo (when he was adopted by the Obu clan) and finally as Yamagata Masakage when he received his fiefdom in Shinano province. Masakage was a close friend of Shingen Takeda and participated at his side in many military campaigns. In 1554, he took part in a military campaign in the south of Shinano province and distinguished himself during the capture of Kannomine castle defended by Chiku Yorimoto.  The latter and his generals surrendered and became vassals of the Takeda clan, other sources report that they were beheaded or that they had already rallied to Shingen since 1552. He was then present at the 3rd battle of Kawanakajima in 1557, during which he penetrated deeply into the territory of the Uesugi, capturing the castle of Otari, which had been securing the road to Itogaiwa. This considerably weakened the strategic position of the Uesugi and accelerated their retreat. According to some reliable sources, his troops attacked while the Uesugi forces were having lunch, driving them out of their positions and setting them on fire. However, the Uesugi counterattacked and fought with honor. Yamagata Masakage and his men wore red armor in battle, which earned them the nickname "red unit" or "fire unit" (as did his brother Toramasa Obu and his warriors). Ii Naomasa of the Tokugawa clan was inspired by this to create his "red demon" units. .</item>


        <item> Baron Yamakawa Hiroshi (山川浩) (December 4, 1845 - March 6, 1898) was a Japanese samurai of the late Edo period who became a famous general of the Japanese Imperial Army in the early Meiji era.He was a servant of Aizu known for his ingenious strategies against the early Meiji government during the Boshin War, he was the first person born in Aizu to write a history of the years before the war, along with his brother Yamakawa Kenjirō. Yamakawa Hiroshi, or from his first name, Yōshichirō (与七郎), was born in Aizuwakamatsu (present-day Fukushima Prefecture), in 1845. His father, Shigekata Yamakawa (山川重固), was a karō (elder) of the Matsudaira clan, and his mother, Tōi (唐衣), was the daughter of another karō family, the Saigō. At the age of 15, Yōshichirōs father died, so he became the head of the family. In 1862, Yōshichirō, now called Shigeyoshi (重栄) or generally, Ōkura (大蔵), accompanied the daimyō Katamori Matsudaira from Aizu to Kyōto when the latter was appointed to the Kyoto Shugoshoku post. After distinguishing himself in the 1863-65 clashes, Yamakawa was allowed to accompany the Shogunates foreign affairs magistrate Hidezane Koide to Russia, where he assisted in negotiations over the delineation of the international border from Karafuto Prefecture to Sakhalin. Back in Japan, he participated in the battle of Toba-Fushimi in the Boshin War, which he survived, and took refuge in Edo.</item>


        <item>Yanagisawa Yoshiyasu (柳沢 吉保, December 31, 1658-December 8, 1714) was a samurai of the Edo period. He was a dignitary of the Tokugawa shogunate and a favorite of Tokugawa Tsunayoshi, the fifth shogun. From a young age, Yoshiyasu served Tsunayoshi and then became his wakashu and finally attained the position of soba yōnin. he was daimyo of the Kawagoe estate and later of the Kōfu estate. He retired in 1709. Having already been named Yasuakira, he received a kanji of the shoguns name and then called himself Yoshiyasu. He built the traditional Japanese garden Rikugi-en in 1695.In general, Yanagisawa is infamous for having helped, supported and encouraged Tokugawa Tsunayoshi in his governmental deviances and having often received the visit of the shogun.If at the beginning, Tsunayoshi - whose abilities as a scholar are inversely proportional to his warrior abilities - is a relatively enlightened despot under the aegis of Hotta Masatoshi, he quickly turns into a despot altogether, soon after Yanagisawa takes over as the main advisor.Thus the law on the protection of dogs, which soon extended to other animals: livestock, birds, insects and even fish (one of the main and traditional sources of food in Japan at the time, along with rice) many people were imprisoned or exiled, considered at the time as a severe sentence of a lower degree than death penalty.</item>

    </string-array>

    <integer-array name="data_photo">
        <item>@drawable/miyamotomusashi</item>
        <item>@drawable/shimazutoyohisa</item>
        <item>@drawable/shimazuyoshihiro</item>
        <item>@drawable/tairamasakudo</item>
        <item>@drawable/takedakatsuyori</item>
        <item>@drawable/takenakahanbei</item>
        <item>@drawable/uesugikenshin</item>
        <item>@drawable/yamagatamasakage</item>
        <item>@drawable/yamakawahiroshi</item>
        <item>@drawable/yanagisawayoshiyasu</item>
    </integer-array>

    <string name="about">Profile</string>
    <string name="profile_name">Rizal Darusman</string>
    <string name="profile_email">21106050080@student.uin-suka.ac.id</string>
    <string name="share">Share</string>
</resources>